Ethan Chennault

2361 Pacific View Ct, San Leandro, CA • +1 (510) 457-5290 • ethanolchennault@gmail.com

Summary Statement

Motivated and ambitious student, currently studying business and computer science at University of California, Irvine. Interested in positions that increase exposure to industry tools while boosting experience and capability in several fields of technology, including software engineering, data analysis, and project management.

Web Technologies

React, Vue, Tailwind, Express, Next.js, Remix, Node.js

Git, GitHub, Linux, Docker, Figma, Drizzle, Prisma

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

Javascript, Python, C++, Java, Typescript, HTML, CSS

Database Technologies

SQL,Postgres, Firebase, Supabase, AWS, MongoDB

Concepts

Data Structures, Algorithms, Requirements Analysis, Integration and Unit testing, SSH, SFTP, Data Modeling

Experience

Research Assistant Irvine, CA

University of California, Irvine

Nov 2024-Present

- Optimized the Makefile for BLANT, a network alignment research tool, reducing build time by 20 percent.
- Utilized React and Express in the development of web applications and interfaces for research projects

Summer Technology Intern

Oakland, CA

Alameda County Information and Technologies Department

June 2022-Aug 2022

- Configured and repaired private networking systems that included switches, firewalls and routers, allowing for faster communications and network connection in three new buildings.
- Deployed Virtual Machines utilizing vSphere for virtual work access to increase productivity.
- Investigated and eliminated cybersecurity intrusions utilizing CrowdStrike.
- Uninstalled and disk wiped nonessential servers in the Oakland data center, optimizing the network.
- Met with clients to determine network requirements for a new office building.

Engineering Intern

San Jose, CA

Hewlett Packard Enterprise

May 2021 to Aug 2021

- Developed and optimized a Python command-line script, increasing developer querying speed of real HPE customer servers by 70 percent.
- Created full coverage software tests to ensure code quality across Windows and Linux operating systems.
- Utilized Git and GitHub to track commits, changes, and monitor test cases.
- Gained insight on server array traffic, data management, and server array software.

Education

University of California, Irvine

September 2023-Present

B.S., Computer Science, B.S Business Information Management

GPA: 3.83, Dean's Honor List

Relevant classes: Intermediate Programming, Data Structure Implementation and Analysis

Member of Sigma Phi Epsilon, Cal Beta Alpha

San Leandro High School

August 2019-June 2023

GPA: 4.0, Honor Roll

Relevant classes: AP Computer Science Principles, AP Computer Science A

Additional

Language Skills: Conversational level in Mandarin

Code Projects: https://github.com/3thanOls

Volunteer Experience: Volunteered with San Leandro Community Food Pantry and San Leandro Main Library